DMITRII NOVIKOV

Tokyo, Japan 807-293-1432 nov.dm.konst@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

As a data analyst, I've worked in various roles, starting as a Marketing Analyst at a gaming company. Then, I transitioned to Data Science, building predictive models at a game publisher. Later, I became a Python programmer, creating data services for analysts, also developed a real-time analytics system for the dating service Pure. Currently, I'm open to opportunities from mid-level to team senior positions. I continuously learn new skills and create online courses for data engineers.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance - Data Engineer Teacher

02/2021 - Current

Wrote two courses on data engineering and ETL. The first course on Airflow (~1700 students), the second on ClickHouse analytical database (~600 students). Both courses are currently the most popular courses on their topic in Russian with an average rating of 4.9.

- stepik.org/course/99527 (Airflow)
- stepik.org/course/100210 (ClickHouse)

pure.app - Senior Data Engineer

Remote

10/2021 - 12/2022

- Creation of web analytics system (FastAPI, RabbitMQ, ClickHouse, Superset)
- Development of streaming and batch ETL scripts (Python, Airflow, ClickHouse).
- Data warehouse modeling (Snow scheme)
- Database administration (ClickHouse, Postgres)

Over the course of the job, created a data warehouse for the company, wrote ETL and implemented reporting. With the help of the implemented solutions, the company was able to abandon the Amplitude service in favor of its own solution.

market-delivery.yandex.ru - Data Engineer

Moscow

11/2019 - 02/2021

- Development of streaming and batch ETL scripts (Python, ClickHouse, Airflow)
- DevOps of analytical infostructure (ClickHouse, Postgres, JupyterHub, Airflow, and Superset, Docker, Ansible)
- Data warehouse modeling (Star and Anchor scheme)

 Over the course of the job, created a data warehouse for the company, wrote ETL and implemented reporting.

EDUCATION

RANEPA

Moscow

Bachelor's degree: Computer Science (Data Science) During the first two years, we studied basic math and economics. Starting from the second year, the focus of study shifted to Data Science.

日本国際工科専門学校 Tokyo

Japanese Language Studied Japanese for a year and a half. Currently preparing for JLPT N3.

LANGUAGES

- Russian (Native)
- English (Upper intermediate)
- 日本語 (初中級 レベル)

SKILLS

Analytical Skills

Statistical analysis, products analysis, market research, A/B testing, forecasting.

Engineering Skills

DB and BigData - MSSQL, Postgres, ClickHouse, BigQuery, Hadoop **Cloud System** - GCP, AWS, Yandex Cloud

Programming - Python, SQL, Scala, R **DevOps** - Docker, Ansible, Git, Bash **ETL** - Apache Airflow, RabbitMQ **BI** - Power BI, Tableau

CERTIFICATIONS

Advanced Python (vk.com)

101xp.com - Data Analyst

Moscow 01/2018 - 10/2019

- Development and data showcases (ClickHouse) and dashboards (Slemma)
- Analyzing the market of game applications, preparing calculators for estimating revenue from new projects
- Creation of revenue forecasting model from user
- Development of ETL scripts and ML applications (Python)
- Daily tasks to evaluate the effectiveness of in-game events Over the course of the work, a revenue forecasting model has been created. Together with the team, we completely overhauled ETL and the analytical reporting system.

gamenet.ru - Marketing Analyst

Moscow 04/2016 - 08/2017

- Development of data view and dashboards using MsSQL and PowerBI
- Preparing monthly reporting for C-level management on ROI
- Calculation of the effectiveness of marketing activities During the period of work marketing reporting was automated and PowerBI tool was implemented.

Freelance - Full Stack Web Developer

Worldwide 01/2012 - 01/2016

- Development of medium complexity websites and single page landing pages (BitrixCRM, PHP)
- Automating the purchase of advertising in Google Ads and Yandex Direct services

- Advanced Database (CSC)
- Advanced Statistics (CSC)
- Mathematics for Data Science (OTUS - 6 month course)
- Data Science (OTUS 6 month course)
- Applied Machine Learning (Yandex)
- R for Linguistics (HSE)

RECOMMENDATIONS

From: Aralov Alexander

Head of Client Analytics at

OZON.ru

Dmitry, the sole DE on my team, built a Clickhouse DWH from scratch, integrating various data sources and creating ETL processes for analysts and data scientists. He also supported DS model deployment, wrote technical specs, and optimized code, demonstrating strong skills and reliability.

From: Nikolay Petrov

Head of Analytics 101xp.com

We worked with Dmitry for about two years, during which he contributed to analytics refactoring and ML implementation. Constantly learning and sharing knowledge, his productivity and ambition set a great example for the team, making him a highly valued team member.